Damn it.
Sial.
Oh, Deacon Kang!
Wah, Diakon Kang!
Come on, that was a pretty nice shot.
Itu pukulan yang bagus.
I want to play a round of golf with you, but I don't seem to be getting any better.
Seharusnya aku ikut kau ke lapangan. Namun, kemampuanku tak kunjung meningkat.
Come on, you can just come.
Datang saja.
Are you signing Ju-eun up
Liburan kali ini, kau akan mengirim Ju-eun ke kursus bahasa juga?
I'm not sure.
Entahlah.
She's still quite young.
Anakku masih kecil.
What are you talking about?
Apa maksudmu?
Kids pick up languages better when they are younger.
Bahasa itu, lebih cepat dipelajari, lebih baik.
You're right.
Benar, 'kan? Sebenarnya aku khawatir.
I'm worried our kids might end up like us if we do nothing and--
Jika dibiarkan, anak-anak akan bernasib seperti kami...
Enough. You're embarrassing us in front of the deacons.
Kenapa bicara begitu di depan para diakon?
But it's true.
Memang begitu.
Your career has no future, and a cop's salary is clear-cut.
Apa kau ada peningkatan? Gaji polisi sudah jelas jumlahnya.
I don't see you getting promoted any time soon.
Entah kapan kau akan naik pangkat.
Well, if we all pray hard together,
Hai, jika kita semua berdoa bersama-sama,
perhaps a miracle will occur.
kita bisa menyaksikan mukjizat.
Amen to that.
Amin.
- Yes. - Well, now that we're on the subject.
- Ya. - Kebetulan kita membahas ini.
It's our pastor,
Pak Pendeta tak datang ibadah minggu lalu. Apa kau dengar sesuatu?
Well, I'm not sure.
Tidak. Aku tak tahu.
I heard from the hair salon
Di salon kecantikan,
that the pastor's wife looked quite anxious for some reason.
ada juga rumor bahwa istri Pendeta tampak sangat cemas.
I haven't been able to get in touch with her recently, so I'm a bit worried.
Aku khawatir, karena sudah lama ia tak bisa dihubungi.
I'll stop by to check in on them when I'm out on patrol later.
Kalau begitu, aku akan mampir saat berpatroli nanti.
Don't worry.
- Jangan khawatir. - Baiklah.
Where do kids go for language learning?
Di mana tempat kursus bahasa yang bagus?
Lately, Canada is...
Belakangan, Kanada...
Korean tidal flats.
Dataran pasang surut Korea.
Recently, interest in tidal flats is increasing
Belakangan, ditemukan bahwa ini menyerap karbon,
as they are known to absorb carbon.
sehingga makin diminati di dunia akademis.
Today we will...
Seorang ahli...
Pastor Kwon.
Pak Pendeta.
We have with us Professor Yoon Ji-hong from Hankuk University.
Ada Prof. Yoon Ji-hong
Hello. I'm Yoon Ji-hong.
Halo, saya Yoon Ji-hong.
Professor Yoon.
Profesor Yoon, dataran pasang surut Korea terdaftar di UNESCO.
designated as UNESCO sites, to be formed. What's your opinion?
Kondisi apa yang membentuk dataran pasang surut ini?
Pastor Kwon?
Pak Pendeta?
First, in order for tidal flats to form,
Agar dataran pasang surut terbentuk,
it is often said
dalam oseanografi,
Pastor Kwon.
Pak Pendeta.
Oh, my God! What is this? What...
Astaga! Apa-apaan ini?
Are you the police?
Apa kau polisi?
What is this?
Apa-apaan ini?
Our species was born with one command to follow.
Spesies kami dilahirkan dengan satu perintah.
"Eat
"Makanlah manusia."
So, I did some research on humans and the human world.
Jadi, aku belajar tentang manusia dan dunianya.
But unlike other species,
Namun, manusia berbeda dengan spesies lainnya.
humans survive using
Manusia bertahan hidup
a very interesting method.
dengan cara yang menarik.
You do not need to be afraid.
Tak perlu takut.
I will make a proposal to you.
Aku hanya ingin memberi penawaran.
I do not believe
Bagimu pun,
it will be a bad deal for you either.
tawaran ini pasti tidak buruk.
If you do not accept,
Jika tidak kau terima,
you will
kau juga
die here too.
mati di sini.
I...
Aku...
do not wish to take over just one human
tak hanya menginginkan satu manusia.
but to become the head of a human organization.
Aku ingin jadi kepala organisasi manusia.
As the head of a human organization,
Setelah itu, aku ingin
I want to parasitize
menjadi parasit
that organization.
di organisasi itu.
What is it with your awkward smile?
Kenapa kau tersenyum canggung?
Is this not the time to have a serious look?
Bukankah seharusnya kita tampak serius?
As expected, you adapt quickly.
Kau beradaptasi dengan cepat.
By the way,
Ah, lalu,
if our plan succeeds...
jika rencana kita berhasil...
shouldn't I at least become an assemblyman
setidaknya, aku harus jadi anggota DPR
to properly assist you?
untuk bisa membantumu.
You can become anything you want.
Kau bisa jadi apa pun yang kau mau.
We will soon control the human organization.
Organisasi manusia akan kita miliki.
SPECIAL PRESS CONFERENCE ON THE PARASITES IN NAMIL-GUN
KONFERENSI PERS KHUSUS MENGENAI PARASIT NAMIL-GUN
Hello.
Halo.
I am Kim Chul-min, Captain of Violent Crimes Team 3.
Aku Kim Chul-min, pemimpin Tim Kasus Kekerasan 3 Kantor Polisi Namil.
Today, I would like to update you
Hari ini, aku akan memberitahukan kemajuan penyelidikan tentang parasit.
Recently, we executed
Baru-baru ini, kepolisian Namil melakukan operasi pemberantasan besar
As a result, we were able to eradicate
Hasilnya, kami telah memusnahkan hampir semua organisme parasit di Namil.
However, we have determined
Namun, masih ada yang bertahan dan bersembunyi di daerah ini.
While the Korean Folk Music Festival will proceed as scheduled,
Jadi, meski festival dan peresmian Balai Peringatan Choi Yong-jae
as mentioned earlier, we urge the public to remain vigilant
sampai pemberantasan sisa-sisa parasit selesai dilaksanakan,
until the parasites are eradicated completely.
kami meminta warga untuk tidak lengah.
Next, it was decided today
Selanjutnya,
by the Personal Information Disclosure Committee to make
sesuai keputusan Komite Pengungkapan Data Pribadi,
this personal information public.
kami ungkapkan hal berikut.
Jeong Su-in, 29 years old.
Jeong Su-in, 29 tahun.
Seol Kyung-hee, 45 years old.
Seol Kyung-hee, 45 tahun.
They are both residents of Namil-gun,
Keduanya penduduk wilayah Namil-gun,
female, and around 160 centimeters tall.
wanita dengan tinggi badan sekitar 160 cm.
The two women pictured here...
Dua orang di foto ini...
That'll be 6,800 won.
Totalnya 6.800 won.
...are extremely dangerous parasites.
...diidentifikasi sebagai parasit. Jika melihat mereka
please send in a tip or report it immediately to the Namil Police Station
harap melapor ke Kantor Polisi Namil atau Satgas Parasit Kepolisian.
This information will be available on the NPA website
Data pribadi ini tersedia untuk dilihat publik
so that all citizens have access to it.
lewat situs web Badan Kepolisian Nasional.
Once again, we ask the public and the media
Sekali lagi, kami mengimbau warga dan media.
for your cooperation and to provide any information you may have.
Kami menantikan kerja sama dan laporan aktif Anda.
Everyone knows what you look like now. Let's be careful.
Wajahmu sudah tersebar. Kita harus hati-hati.
But why are they taking such drastic measures?
Kenapa mereka memancing begini?
The mayor is coming to the Korean Folk Music Festival.
Wali Kota Namcheon akan datang ke festival itu.
If Heidi and that monster show up as well, things will get really messy.
Jika Heidi dan monster itu datang bersama, pasti ribut.
So it will try to switch over to the mayor's body then.
Saat itu, ia akan pindah ke tubuh Wali Kota.
KYUNG-HEE
KAK KYUNG-HEE
Hello?
Halo.
It is your sister.
Ini kakakmu.
You crazy shit. Don't you say those words to me!
Dasar bajingan gila, jangan bicara sembarangan.
Let us meet.
Ayo bertemu.
You think I've lost my mind? Why would I meet you?
Kau kira aku gila, mau menemuimu?
Tell this to my kin that you are with,
Berikan pada sesamaku yang di sampingmu. Ia lebih bisa diajak bicara.
Fuck off.
Berengsek.
It's me.
Ini aku.
You must know you and I are in the same boat if you saw the news.
Jika sudah lihat berita, kau tahu situasi kita sama.
Let us meet at once.
Ayo bertemu sekarang.
I will be waiting at Cheongil Botanical Garden.
Kutunggu di Kebun Raya Cheongil.
Are you really going to meet her?
Apa? Kau mau menemuinya?
The monster that killed Mr. Chul-min
Parasit yang membunuh dan merebut tubuh Paman
is now trying to become the mayor of a big city.
ingin jadi wali kota dengan ratusan ribu warga.
So what? What can the two of us actually do?
Jadi, apa yang bisa kita berdua lakukan?
That's exactly why we need more people on our side.
Karena itu kita butuh satu orang lagi.
PARASYTE: THE GREY
PARASYTE: THE GREY
Good work.
Kerja bagus.
Thank you.
Ya.
Well, that was a good briefing.
Aku sudah dengar pengarahannya.
Oh, thank you.
Ah, ya.
I think it went well, just as we agreed.
Semua berjalan sesuai rencana. Apa ada masalah?
No, I wouldn't say it's a problem.
Tidak, bukan masalah.
I mean, you put in so much effort to protect Jeong Su-in this whole time.
Tetapi, kau berjuang melindungi Jeong Su-in selama ini.
But today, it seems like you've had a change of heart.
Ternyata, kau sudah berpindah pihak.
Is that what you think?
Begitu?
The safety of the public should come before any personal feelings, right?
Keamanan warga lebih penting dari perasaan pribadi.
Really?
Begitu?
When we raided Saejin Church, not long ago,
Saat kita menggerebek gereja,
you found something that belonged to her, didn't you?
kau menemukan barang Su-in di sana, 'kan?
The thing you hid in your pocket.
Kau sembunyikan di sakumu.
Then you met her at that theme park to confirm if it was hers.
Kau bertemu dia di taman hiburan untuk mengonfirmasi.
What was the item?
Benda apa itu?
Does that really matter right now?
Apa itu penting sekarang?
Whether you're trying to deny it
Apa kau berusaha menghindar atau benar-benar tidak ingat,
I can't really tell.
aku tidak tahu.
He's very soft-hearted, you know?
Hatinya sangat lembut.
We have to get going now, okay?
Kami permisi dulu.
Let's go.
Ayo pergi.
That one is suspicious of me.
Dia mencurigaiku.
Let's get rid of it now.
Ayo kita singkirkan dia.
- We need to make it look natural. - How?
- Kita butuh cara yang alami. - Bagaimana?
With the method humans use.
Gunakan cara manusia,
By utilizing an organization.
yaitu organisasi.
Is this the right place? You agreed to meet here?
Benar di sini? Kalian janji bertemu di sini?
I can sense it.
Aku merasakannya. Dia ada di dalam.
Why here, of all places?
Kenapa harus di tempat macam ini?
You know it'll be a disaster if Heidi and that thing fight.
Jika Heidi dan dia bertarung di sini, pasti ribut.
She will know that too.
- Dia pasti tahu itu. - Sial, mengejutkan saja.
You stay here.
Kau tunggu di sini saja.
Why?
Kenapa?
Your thirst for revenge makes you a liability right now.
Saat ini, keinginanmu untuk balas dendam lebih mengkhawatirkan.
Why did you ask to meet?
Kenapa kau ingin bertemu?
To punish the one who betrayed our kin.
Untuk menghukum dia yang mengkhianati sesama.
The one that jumped from Pastor Kwon to Detective Kim Chul-min.
Dia yang dahulu jadi Pendeta lalu jadi Detektif Kim Chul-min itu
I must kill him.
harus dibunuh.
Did you not understand when he went on the news to provoke us?
Kau tak tahu, ia memancing kita lewat siaran itu?
It is an obvious trap.
Ini jelas jebakan.
He is trying to drag us into a scheme.
Ia berusaha menyeret kita.
It does not matter.
Aku tidak peduli.
I am going to kill him.
Akan kubunuh dia.
But he is already parasitizing a human organization.
Namun, ia sudah jadi parasit di organisasi manusia.
Organizations are truly amazing.
Organisasi itu luar biasa.
A single creature may be weak,
Satu individu mungkin lemah,
but an organization formed by many of them is highly resilient and powerful.
tetapi satu organisasi punya daya tahan dan kekuatan yang luar biasa.
He understood this.
Dia memahami itu.
Are you asking me for help?
Kau minta bantuanku?
The owner of this body may agree, but I do not.
Inangku mungkin setuju, tetapi aku tidak.
You want to kill him too, do you not?
Pasti kau pun ingin membunuhnya.
It is an irrational choice that goes against survival.
Itu pilihan yang tidak logis untuk kelangsungan hidup.
Survival?
Kelangsungan hidup?
Is survival all that matters to you?
Apa itu adalah segalanya?
Look at this man.
Lihat pria ini.
He came at me even though he knew that he could die.
Ia tahu bisa mati, tetapi ia menyerangku.
It was definitely not a rational choice.
Itu pilihan yang tak logis.
But I can now understand what this man is feeling.
Namun, kini aku memahami perasaan pria ini.
I came to understand it when our kin was killed by him.
Aku sadar saat sesamaku dibunuh oleh parasit itu.
Damn it, how dare you say that you understand me!
Sial. Beraninya berkata kau memahamiku?
We can neither live independently
Kita tak bisa hidup mandiri atau meneruskan spesies lewat reproduksi.
The only thing we can do is parasitize humans and eat them.
Kita hanya bisa jadi parasit di tubuh manusia dan memakan mereka.
It's your fault for being born a parasite.
Siapa suruh lahir seperti itu?
What's wrong with him?
Ada apa dengan dia?
That is right.
Benar.
We were not given a choice,
Itu bukan pilihan kami. Jadi, aku harus mempertanyakan.
"What is the reason for our existence?"
"Kenapa kami harus bertahan hidup?"
Then one of our kin answered.
Lalu, salah satu dari kami berkata
That we must protect each other.
bahwa kami harus saling melindungi...
That we must be able to rely on each other.
dan jadi seseorang yang bisa diandalkan.
And that we must create an organization and survive together.
Jadi, kami harus membentuk organisasi dan hidup bersama.
The one who gave us the meaning of our existence...
Yang memberitahukan makna kehidupan...
is the one I want to kill.
adalah dia yang ingin kubunuh.
Don't be an idiot.
Jangan bodoh.
The bastards who say that kind of stuff
Para bajingan yang bicara begitu
are the first to backstab others for their own survival.
adalah yang pertama menghancurkan organisasi untuk bertahan.
Do you know what he is after?
- Kau tahu apa yang dia incar? - Ingin tahu?
The festival is happening tomorrow.
Besok, ada Festival Musik Tradisional. Wali Kota Namcheon datang.
I'm sure that bastard is after the mayor's head.
Mungkin, bajingan itu mengincar Wali Kota Namcheon.
If he takes over the mayor's brain,
Jika ia mengambil alih kepala Wali Kota, lebih sulit bagi kalian untuk bertahan
In the end, you will be killed by humans.
Akhirnya, kalian mati di tangan manusia.
What will the both of you do?
Apa rencana kalian?
We're going to kill that bastard
Sebelum bajingan itu membunuh Wali Kota, kami akan membunuh dia.
And the next to die
Setelah itu,
will be you, got it?
giliranmu.
I'm gonna tear that fucking head of yours from my sister's body.
Akan kucabut kepala kotormu dari tubuh kakakku.
The latter part of your plan will not go as you wish,
Bagian akhir itu tak akan terjadi,
but until then, we have the same goal.
tetapi di bagian awalnya, kita memiliki tujuan yang sama.
OPENING CEREMONY OF CHOI YONG-JAE MEMORIAL HALL, A CIVILIAN ARMY LEADER
PERESMIAN BALAI PERINGATAN CHOI YONG-JAE
Did the results I requested come out yet?
Apa hasil yang kuminta sudah keluar?
Okay, I'll be right there.
Ya, aku segera ke sana.
This is the autopsy image of Hunting Dog Number One.
Ini foto autopsi mayat Anjing Pemburu 1.
And this is an image
Lalu, ini
of a weapon that the parasites transform their bodies into
bagian tubuh organisme parasit
that was seen in various cases.
yang dijadikan senjata di kasus lain.
Did you check to see if it can be reproduced in a similar way?
Sudah kau periksa, apa hal serupa bisa dibuat?
We made a similar cross-section with a kitchen knife
Kami buat bilah serupa menggunakan pisau dapur
and tried to recreate a cut on the neck.
dan menyayat luka serupa di leher.
It did make a similar pattern.
Hasilnya, polanya mirip.
So, you're saying it's possible to use a purposely crafted weapon
Jadi, jika ada yang membunuh dengan senjata menyerupai parasit,
to manipulate it as if a parasite did the killing, right?
orang akan mengira parasit yang membunuh korbannya?
Yes, unfortunately, it's a point we overlooked.
Ya, sebenarnya kita melewatkan hal ini.
But it's definitely possible that it was manipulated.
Ada kemungkinan ini dimanipulasi.
Should we reinvestigate the case?
Haruskah kita selidiki ulang sekarang?
No.
Tidak.
Nothing is certain yet. Let's keep this to ourselves for now.
Kita belum yakin, jadi rahasiakan saja untuk saat ini.
Yes, ma'am.
Baik.
Yes, I'm at the station.
Ya, aku di kantor.
What?
Apa?
Oh, Captain Choi.
Ibu Choi,
We've received a tip-off.
ada laporan masuk.
The same symbol found in Saejin Church was discovered in a church in Gangwon-do.
Lambang yang ada di Gereja Saejin juga ditemukan di sebuah gereja di Gangwon-do.
A tip-off?
Laporan?
When and how did we get the report?
Kapan dan dari mana?
Captain Kim received an anonymous tip-off this morning
Pak Kim Chul-min dapat informasi anonim dan lapor ke markas.
Captain Kim?
Detektif Kim Chul-min?
Now that the parasites in Namil-gun are almost eradicated,
Karena parasit di Namil-gun hampir habis,
I believe your team should be deployed to Gangwon-do.
lebih baik Tim 3 diarahkan ke Gangwon-do.
What are your thoughts on this?
Bagaimana menurutmu?
Shouldn't we check if the report is reliable first, sir?
Sebaiknya kredibilitas informasi itu diperiksa dahulu.
It should be Team Grey who goes and confirms that.
Tim Grey, kalian yang harus melakukannya. Kalau bisa, sekarang.
What about the ones remaining here?
Lalu, sisa parasit di sini?
The local police force should be able to handle that much.
Kepolisian setempat bisa mengendalikan mereka dengan baik.
Team Grey should immediately move to Gangwon-do and begin subjugation there.
Tim Grey, segera pindah ke Gangwon-do dan mulai pembasmian.
The advance party, get ready!
Tim pilihan, bersiap!
- Go over to that side now. - Yes, sir.
Kau ke sana.
What are they so busy doing?
Sibuk apa mereka?
They're providing security escort at the festival. It's for the mayor.
Mereka mengamankan festival. Mungkin karena Wali Kota Namcheon.
Yes, this is Jeong Su-in's cell phone.
Ya, ini ponsel Jeong Su-in.
It's me.
Ini aku.
Jeong Su-in? Or that monster?
Jeong Su-in? Atau monster itu?
Sure, it is the monster you want to kill.
Ya, aku monster yang ingin kau bunuh.
At this rate, I might grow fond of you.
Kalau begini, kita bisa akrab.
What do you want?
Ada apa?
We made a mistake.
Kami membuat kesalahan.
As you said, Detective Kang is not a parasite.
Seperti katamu, Detektif Kang Won-seok bukan parasit.
He is a human
Dia manusia
He killed the Hunting Dog you cherished so dearly
Ia membunuh anjing pemburu kesayanganmu
and helped the pastor transfer himself to Captain Kim's body.
dan membantu Pendeta memasuki jasad Kim Chul-min.
You said they were both parasites.
Kau bilang, mereka berdua parasit.
But now he's just a traitor?
Kini, kau sebut komplotan?
This came directly from a parasite who was on the same side as the pastor.
Ini kudengar dari parasit yang pernah sekelompok dengannya.
But there is an even bigger problem.
Ada masalah yang lebih besar.
Their ultimate goal
Target mereka adalah
is to kill the mayor at the festival and switch over to his body.
membunuh Wali Kota di festival dan masuk ke tubuhnya.
- What? - Believe what I am saying.
- Apa? - Percayalah padaku.
We are going there right now
Kami akan pergi ke sana dan membunuhnya.
If we fail, someone else has to do it and succeed.
Jika kami gagal, harus ada orang lain yang berhasil.
So you should also come and help in killing him.
Datanglah ke sini dan bantu kami membunuhnya.
What did she say? How did she react?
Bagaimana reaksinya?
Nothing yet.
Belum ada.
I will now save my energy for the festival which will take place soon.
Aku akan menghemat tenaga untuk festival sebentar lagi.
Sure, of course. Go to sleep.
Baiklah. Tidurlah.
But the pastor Kang Won-seok brought along cut off his head.
Kepalanya dipenggal oleh pendeta yang dibawa Kang Won-seok.
And that bastard took over his body and is pretending to be him!
Pendeta itu mengambil alih tubuh Paman
Turn the car around.
Putar balik.
I'll take full responsibility. Turn around now.
Aku yang tanggung jawab. Putar balik.
Yes, ma'am.
Baik.
Sir, look over here.
Pak, sebelah sini!
Over here, sir.
Lihat ke sini!
Nothing to note so far.
Belum banyak pergerakan.
Maybe it's waiting for us to create a scene.
Mungkin ia menunggu kita buat keributan.
How is it over there?
Bagaimana di sana?
It's the same here.
Di sini pun sama.
- Should we get going too? - No.
- Haruskah kami bergerak? - Tidak.
For now, let's just wait as Heidi said.
Seperti kata Heidi, kita tunggu saja.
If you two come close, that bastard will notice right away.
Begitu kalian berdua mendekat, dia akan sadar.
Maintain your distance.
Jadi, jaga jarak.
Come if something happens. I'll be monitoring from here.
Jika ada sesuatu, baru datanglah. Aku akan awasi.
- Sir, you should try some hotteok. -   Oh, sure.
Coba hotteok ini.
- Oh, welcome. - Hello.
- Selamat datang. - Ya.
It looks so delicious.
Wah, kelihatannya enak.
Okay, a big one to-go, specially for Mr. Mayor.
Hotteok istimewa untuk Pak Wali Kota.
Here you go. It's hot, so please be careful.
Silakan. Ini masih panas.
- Oh God! - Oh no.
- Astaga.
It's quite chewy and delicious.
Wah, ini kenyal dan enak sekali.
Is this made with local flour?
Apa ini, terbuat dari gandum lokal?
- No, it's imported flour. - What?
- Ini gandum impor. - Apa?
But Namil-gun is famous
Tetapi, semua makanan Namil-gun
for making all kinds of food so deliciously.
terkenal dengan rasa rumahan.
- Amazing cooking skills are the specialty! - Correct.
Rasa rumahan yang khas.
Hey, don't just stand here.
Jangan di sini. Periksa alur pengunjung dan berjaga di poin berikutnya.
- Yes, sir. - Sir.
- Baik. - Ya.
Is this necessary?
Apa harus seperti ini?
Even if human cops are there,
Meski ada polisi manusia, jika Heidi dan aku menyerang bersamaan,
Heidi is not cautious because she is afraid...
Heidi berhati-hati bukan karena takut...
but because of me.
melainkan karena aku.
She doesn't want me in danger.
Ia takut aku dalam bahaya.
She was so unlucky.
Sial sekali dia.
Out of all the people out there, she came inside of me while I was dying.
Di antara begitu banyak orang, ia datang padaku saat aku sekarat.
That's why she couldn't fully take over me.
Jadi, ia tak bisa mengambil alih.
She had to save me first in order for her to live.
Agar bisa hidup, ia harus menyelamatkanku.
So, in the end, she became an incomplete being
Akhirnya, ia jadi makhluk tak sempurna
who can only use her strength for 10 to 15 minutes at a time.
yang bisa memakai kekuatannya 10 atau 15 menit saja.
She can't transfer herself into another body like you or the others.
Ia tidak bisa pindah ke tubuh lain seperti kau dan lainnya.
So,
Pantas saja,
that is why she is powerful.
kau kuat.
What?
Apa?
Generally, when our kin first takes over a human body and is able to control it,
Biasanya, saat kami pertama kali mengambil alih tubuh manusia,
we no longer consider that body a part of ourselves.
kami tak menganggapnya tubuh kami.
It is similar to humans driving a car.
Seperti saat manusia mengendarai mobil.
If it breaks, though inconvenient, you can throw it away.
Tak nyaman jika rusak, tetapi bisa dibuang.
But Heidi could not do that.
Namun, Heidi tak bisa melakukan itu.
She had to protect a part of herself.
Ia harus melindungi bagian dari dirinya.
That is why Heidi had to be strong
Jadi, Heidi harus kuat
and always fought so desperately
dan selalu bertarung sekuat tenaga
in order to protect you.
untuk melindungimu.
It's on the move.
Dia bergerak.
What? Where?
Di mana?
Mr. Mayor! This way!
Pak, menghindar!
Enter the festival grounds now.
Masuk lokasi festival.
Move!
Bergerak!
Go to the mayor.
Pergi ke Pak Wali Kota!
- Yes, ma'am. - Yes.
Baik.
Have they lost their fucking minds?
Sial, apakah mereka gila?
Come on, evacuate now!
Cepat mengungsi!
Quick! Get up.
Cepat bergerak!
Hey, they're taking the mayor into a building, okay?
Mereka membawa Wali Kota ke dalam gedung! Cepat kemari!
Jeong Su-in, it's time to surrender!
Jeong Su-in! Menyerah sekarang!
Come out!
Keluar!
I will take care of that woman. You go ahead.
Biar kuurus wanita itu. Pergilah.
Good. Do as we say now.
Bagus. Sekarang, patuhi kami.
Damn it.
Berengsek.
Do you really need to kill me?
Apa kau harus membunuhku?
Our goal is simply to live.
Tujuan kami hanya bertahan hidup.
I do not want to hurt anyone, including you.
Aku tidak ingin melukaimu atau siapa pun.
The choice is yours.
Buatlah pilihan.
Over here.
Di sini.
What the hell?
Apa-apaan ini?
The head is missing.
Kepalanya hilang.
Where?
Di mana?
The back parking lot? Got it.
Tempat parkir belakang? Baik.
There's a car waiting for you, sir.
Mobil Anda di tempat parkir belakang.
The back parking lot.
Tempat parkir belakang.
What the hell?
Apa? Sial!
Hey!
Hai!
We're on your side.
Aku di pihakmu!
It cannot survive for long without a host. You take the mayor--
Ia tak bertahan lama tanpa tubuh. Bawa Wali Kota...
Hey, are you okay?
Hai, kau baik-baik saja?
To you,
Aku...
I am sorry.
minta maaf padamu.
How long can you hold on?
Berapa lama kau bisa bertahan?
There's no one here
Tidak ada tubuh...
you can transfer yourself to.
Tidak ada tubuh, bagaimana ini?
What do we do?
Bagaimana?
Where do we have to go?
Kita harus ke mana?
- Where? - The back parking lot.
- Jawab. - Tempat parkir belakang.
- We need to go there. - The back?
- Ke sana. - Belakang?
Hurry up and go!
Cepat pergi!
To the right!
Ke kanan!
Take him and run quickly.
Bawa dia dan cepat kabur.
Heidi, Su-in, I'll come back to get you!
Heidi, Su-in, aku pasti akan kembali!
- Hey, hurry up and go! - Mr. Mayor!
- Hai! Cepat pergi! - Wali Kota!
- Are you okay? - Get him out of here.
- Kau baik-baik saja? - Pergi sejauh mungkin!
Mutant.
Varian.
When you came to the church,
Hari itu, di gereja,
why did you decide to side with humans instead of us?
kenapa kau memihak manusia, dan bukan kami?
I did not think you would accept a mutant like me.
Aku tidak mengira, kalian akan menerima varian sepertiku.
What made you think that way?
Kenapa berpikir begitu?
You were too similar to humans.
Kau sangat mirip manusia.
Similar to humans, I see.
Mirip manusia?
Yes, you are right.
Ya, kau benar.
Neither I nor humans accept a mutant like you.
Baik aku maupun manusia, tidak menerima varian sepertimu.
But that is what makes the human organization powerful.
Namun, itulah kekuatan organisasi manusia.
They call the majority normal and the minority of mutants abnormal.
Mayoritas dianggap normal,
They strengthen the organization by obtaining the support of the majority.
Mereka memperkuat organisasi dengan dukungan mayoritas.
And the great life form,
Begitulah lahirnya
possesses a power that is incomparable to a life form that is fragile like us.
dan makhluk lemah seperti kita
Human organizations sacrifice many people for a single purpose.
Organisasi manusia mengorbankan banyak orang untuk suatu tujuan.
And after they achieve their goal,
Lalu, setelah mencapai tujuan itu,
they commemorate the one person who served as their leader.
yang diingat hanya pemimpin mereka seorang.
As you can see in this memorial hall.
Seperti balai peringatan ini.
Jeong Su-in!
Jeong Su-in!
Heidi.
Heidi.
Su-in.
Su-in.
Goddamn it.
Sial.
Do you remember the command we were given the moment we were born?
Kau ingat perintah yang kita terima saat kita lahir?
"Take over a human brain."
"Ambil alih kepala manusia."
Maybe it didn't just mean
Arti perintah itu
to take over the physical head of a human
bukan hanya tentang merebut kepala manusia,
but rather to take over the head of a great creature
melainkan juga kepala dari organisasi manusia. Bukan begitu?
Join me now.
Sekarang, bergabunglah denganku.
If we join hands,
Kau dan aku
we will be able to take over the head of the human organization.
mampu mengambil alih kepala organisasi manusia.
Both of you, freeze.
Jangan bergerak.
Shoot her.
Tembak.
If you don't want to lose your head, shoot her!
Jika tidak ingin kepalamu meledak, tembak dia! Cepat!
Did you know I was going to shoot him?
Kau sudah menduga aku akan menembak dia?
No. I do not have the ability to predict such things.
Tidak, aku tak punya kemampuan menduga hal seperti itu.
Then why did you attack him instead of me?
Namun, kenapa kau menyerang dia, bukan aku?
I trusted you.
Aku percaya padamu.
Jeong Su-in is a strange girl.
Jeong Su-in orang yang aneh.
She has been hurt numerous times by humans,
Berkali-kali ia dilukai manusia,
but no matter what, she does not give up her trust in them.
tetapi ia tak menyerah untuk mempercayai seseorang.
Instead, she extends her hand to others first.
Ia mengulurkan tangan lebih dahulu.
That is who she is.
Begitulah dia.
I wanted to copy
Aku ingin mengikuti
her trust in people.
kepercayaan Su-in.
Deep inside, Jeong Su-in longs for people.
Di lubuk hatinya, Jeong Su-in merindukan manusia.
She wants to live among people.
Ia ingin hidup di antara orang-orang.
Su-in!
Su-in!
Jeong Su-in! Su-in, are you okay?
Jeong Su-in! Kau baik-baik saja?
Please take care of Su-in.
Tolong jaga Su-in.
Su-in. Oh, what do I do? Hey, Jeong Su-in!
Su-in! Bagaimana ini? Jeong Su-in!
Hey! What the hell happened?
Hai! Sial, apa yang terjadi?
Su-in, wake up.
Su-in!
Captain.
Ibu Choi.
Take them to the hospital quickly.
Bawa mereka ke rumah sakit.
Isn't Jeong Su-in a parasite?
Bukankah Jeong Su-in parasit?
Those two are just normal humans.
Mereka hanya orang biasa.
- What are you mewing? - What?
- Kau sedang apa? - Apa?
I'm working.
Bekerja.
When will you be done?
Kapan selesai?
In two hours?
Dua jam lagi.
You're working too hard. Isn't it tough on you?
Kau giat sekali bekerja. Tidak lelah?
What about you? How have you been?
Bagaimana denganmu?
Me?
Aku?
I joined a new organization.
Aku bergabung ke organisasi baru.
You joined another one after all you've been through?
Masuk geng lagi, setelah diperlakukan begitu?
It's not like I can start one myself.
Aku tak bisa membuatnya sendiri.
I can't be a lone wolf forever.
Aku pun tak bisa hidup sendiri.
Besides, the world is a tough place.
Dunia ini tidak semudah itu.
Here.
Untukmu.
It's impressive, right?
Keren, 'kan? Seol Kang-woo dari Tim Grey.
Captain Choi got me this entire outfit.
Semua baju ini pun dari Ibu Choi Jun-kyung.
I have insurance now.
Ada asuransi juga.
Are you jealous?
Kau iri, 'kan?
I thought about it a lot.
Aku berpikir panjang.
But what choice do I have but to give it another shot?
Namun, bagaimana lagi? Harus percaya sekali lagi.
Yeah.
Ya,
Good for you.
baguslah.
What?
Kenapa?
Did you have something to say?
Ada yang mau kau katakan?
Actually, I received a letter yesterday.
Kemarin, aku mendapat surat.
The thing is...
Ini...
Heidi was the one who sent it.
Heidi yang mengirimnya.
She could have left it for you herself,
Ia bisa berikan langsung padamu,
but she asked me to read it aloud for you in a human voice.
tetapi ia minta kubacakan dengan suara manusia.
Here we go.
Aku mulai.
"Hi, Jeong Su-in."
"Halo, Jeong Su-in."
Okay, I won't joke around.
Aku tak akan bercanda.
"This may sound awkward since this is my first letter,
“Mungkin canggung karena aku belum pernah menulis surat.
so please understand."
Kuharap kau mengerti.
"I thought about the meaning
Aku memikirkan tentang arti keberadaanku, seperti yang dibicarakan sesamaku.
"I have not come to a conclusion yet,
Aku belum menemukan jawabannya,
but I am glad that you are the host
tetapi aku bersyukur karena kau inangku
that I parasitized and that I failed to fully take over your brain."
dan karena aku tak bisa mengambil alih kepalamu sepenuhnya."
This sentence right here. You need to read this yourself.
Kalimat selanjutnya, kau saja yang baca.
I can't bring myself to read it.
Aku tak bisa membacanya.
Su-in!
Su-in!
Captain Choi said she has a spot for you on the team.
Ibu Choi Jun-kyung bilang, ada tempat bagimu.
Don't be such a loner. Just give me a call if you wanna join.
Jangan sendirian. Jika mau bergabung, hubungi aku.
See you.
Sampai jumpa.
WHETHER YOU LIKE IT OR NOT, YOU ARE NOT ALONE
SUKA ATAU TIDAK, KAU TIDAK SENDIRIAN
So, who is this person?
Jadi, siapa dia?
He says he's an investigative journalist
Katanya, ia reporter
and claims to be the top expert when it comes to parasites.
yang ahli dalam bidang organisme parasit.
And he says he has some very important information.
Dia menghubungi karena punya informasi yang sangat penting.
What? Are you sure he's not a nut job?
Apa? Jangan-jangan hanya orang gila.
Thank you for waiting.
Terima kasih sudah menunggu. Ini Ibu Choi Jun-kyung dari Tim Grey.
Who are you?
Siapa kau?
Hello, my name is Shinichi Izumi.
Halo, namaku Shinichi Izumi.